There's so many of them, huh?
Yeah, there are.
I know, right?
It's like this pretty much every day.
By the way, is Yui feeling any better?
Well, she got a good night's
sleep, so I think she's okay.
I don't know, you tell me.
Has this ever happened to her before?
We have no idea.
You see, we found her on floor
22, wandering in the forest.
The poor thing.
She's lost her memory. Oh.
That's the reason we came here.
We thought maybe someone in the town
of Beginnings might know who she is.
You live here.
Have you ever seen her before?
Sorry, I haven't.
I mean, there are a lot of kids
in town, but I've never seen her.
When the game started, a lot of the children
suffered severe psychological trauma.
I couldn't stand by and do nothing,
so I moved to this church and made
it a safe place for them to live.
I walk through the town every
day looking for kids like these,
kids who might need my help?
but in all this time, I've
never seen her before.
Back to square one.
Sorry to bother you. I'm Yulier.
And you're with the army, right?
I hope you're not here to start
trouble because of yesterday.
God, no.
In fact, I'm here to thank you.
You did right by putting
those men in their place.
Actually, I came here to ask
the two of you for your help.
Seriously?
It's so painful that I've ever seen.
I've never seen a long time.
I've been worried about this past year.
I've been seeing a long
time in the future.
Here is my heart,
and I'm filled with my heart.
In my dreams, I can't breathe.
I can't breathe, I can't breathe.
I can't breathe.
Kizuku yoy wa taashi Game ga yireba.
Nagai yume miru koko rohan soeigen de.
I wanna always be with this.
I'm giving everything I have.
When the guild was formed, we,
well, actually it was our
leader, Thinker, he never wanted.
it to turn into the kind of
dictatorial organization it's become.
At first,
the mission of the guild was
to share information and food,
equally among as many players as possible.
But then the guild grew
too large, didn't it?
Right.
And after much infighting,
one man became very powerful.
His name is Gabe.
Gabe and his group became
stronger and stronger,
monopolizing all the best
monster spawn points.
They're out of control now,
extorting other players under
the pretext of collecting taxes.
It was obvious Gabe didn't
care about clearing the game,
and that made a lot of people mad.
He had to do something to get
back in their good graces,
so he sent the highest level
players he had to the front lines.
Korvats!
Gibao was denounced after spearheading
that massacre that's when we started to.
Seriously consider kicking
him out of the guild for
good and now that he's scared
and getting desperate he's
decided to eliminate thinker
he set a trap and stranded
thinker deep inside a dungeon
can't he teleport out does he?
have any weapons.
He didn't take anything with him.
Gabe told him he wanted to talk unarmed.
Thinker believed him.
That was three days ago.
He's been gone that long?
Can't he find his way
out?
The dungeon is the highest
level we've seen so far.
He can't get out of there on his own.
As his second in command,
this is my responsibility.
But the problem is, my level
isn't high enough to reach him.
And Gabe is using his influence to
keep the rest of the Army from helping
me when I heard the two of the most
powerful players anyone seen were in town.
I thought this is my
chance I tracked you down
because I need your help
Kirito Asuna I beg you.
For thinker's sake please
help me rescue him from that
dungeon if you think we
can help get thinker out of
there we'd be glad to help
you however well the thing
is we'd like to make sure
you're telling the truth.
I'm sorry I know we just met
and I'm asking a lot from you.
But when I think about him trapped alone
in there I feel like I'm going insane.
It's okay mommy everything she's
been telling you is the truth.
Yui you mean you can tell mm-hmm I
don't know how I know she is but she is.
If anything, I'd rather trust her and
regret it than not trust her and regret it.
Let's go.
It'll all work out.
Right?
Whatever you say, Mr.
Easygoing.
Okay, we'll help.
I just hope we're strong enough to do it.
Thank you so much.
I know what it feels like
to want to save someone.
Especially someone you care for.
Stay here and wait for us, okay? No!
I'm coming, too!
Oh, come on, Yui.
Don't you want to stay here with me?
No!
Great.
Now we get to see your rebellious side.
Hey, this is serious.
It's too dangerous for you to
come along with us this time.
I'm going, too!
I never knew this dungeon was
under the Town of Beginnings.
I know.
There wasn't anything like
this during the beta test.
I think the dungeon opens up to reveal
more as the floors above are cleared.
I bet Gabe was planning on
keeping this place all to himself.
Exclusive access to
spawns can be profitable.
The thing is, the monsters here
are usually around level 60.
He wouldn't be able to do much hunting.
This is the entrance.
Don't worry, I'm not afraid.
No, it's okay.
believe it or not she's a heck
of a lot tougher than she looks
mm-hmm she'll make a fine
Swordsman someday we should get going
I feel like I should apologize.
He's doing all the fighting.
Oh no, he's happy out there.
Really, he loves getting his battle on.
We're pretty far down,
are we almost there?
Thinker hasn't moved from
this position for a while now.
It could be a safe zone, but I'm not sure.
If we can reach it, maybe we
can use a teleport crystal.
Whew!
Man, I fought my butt off!
I should have helped you.
No, not at all. I had a blast.
Besides, they dropped some items.
Really?
You get anything good?
Uh-huh.
What is that?
It's scavenged toad meat.
You mean those frogs?
Hey, the weirder the meat,
the better the taste.
Maybe you can cook it up later.
Not on your life!
What the hell?
Oh, come on, what'd you do that for?
Damn it. Okay, fine.
What am I gonna do with these?
No, no, no, no! Asuna!
It's good meat!
Get me rid of it!
But it's delicious!
You just have to pull this one!
You smile! Shut up! Huh?
I've never ever seen you smile before!
Huh?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Come on. Let's go.
Look, it's a safe zone.
There's a player inside.
It's Thinker.
Wait, don't
Yulier!
Finker!
No, stay away!
The corridor's rigged!
Stop! Wait, Yulia! Come back!
Yulia, take her to the safe zone
and wait for us there, okay?
Okay.
Mommy! Come on.
Asuna, use a teleport crystal and get
Yui and the others out of here now.
I can't see its data with my ID skill.
It could be as strong
as something from 490.
I can buy you time.
Just get everyone out of here.
No way am I leaving you here.
I'll catch up. Move it!
Mommy!
Take care of Yui!
Run while you still have a chance!
Asuna! No! We can't leave! Hurry!
Kirito!
Yuri, no!
You're dangerous!
Come back!
What are you doing?
Get away from it! Huey!
Daddy, Mommy, it's okay.
Huey!
An immortal object.
I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Yui? Yui?
Daddy, Mommy.
Don't worry.
I remember everything.
Yui, say something. And...
you remember who you are?
Yes.
Kirito Asuna.
Everything in the world of Sword Art
Online is controlled by a single,
massive system.
The system is called Cardinal.
It was designed to operate entirely on
its own, without any human intervention.
Its function is to regulate the balance
of SAO according to its own discretion.
From monsters and NPC AI, to
drop rates for items and money,
everything here is controlled by the
processes the Cardinal program executes.
That includes the psychological
care of the players.
Mental Health Counseling
Program, Prototype 1.
Codename, Huey.
That is who I am.
Your program?
An AI?
I was designed to put
players at ease with me.
That's why I was given the ability
to emulate complex emotions.
Nothing about me is real.
Nothing.
Not even my tears.
I'm so sorry, Asuna.
Oh, Yui.
But then, what about your amnesia?
Can that even happen to an AI?
Two years ago,
on the day of the official launch,
and for reasons I never understood,
the Cardinal program banned me from
interacting with any of the players.
I wasn't allowed to assist them.
I couldn't do anything except continue
monitoring their mental states.
Their situation, in a word, was horrible.
No, don't!
Terror, despair, rage...
People were overcome by negative feelings.
Some of them couldn't take it.
They went insane.
Under normal circumstances,
my function would have been to
go to such players immediately,
but I wasn't permitted
any contact with them.
Little by little, errors began piling
up inside of me, and I fell apart
Then,
one day I saw two players
Their mental parameters were
vastly different from anything
I'd seen among the others
There was joy and peace
and there was something more
I wandered through the playing field
hoping to get as close to both of you as i
could without being detected so that's
why you were in the forest yes that's why
i've wanted to meet the two of you for the
longest time that's
strange isn't it it should
be impossible for me to think things like
that i'm not human i'm a program after all
yui maybe what you're feeling
are real human emotions?
I don't know.
I'm confused.
Nothing makes sense.
I don't know what's happened to me.
You aren't just some program anymore.
The system can't control you.
Listen, if you want something,
all you have to do is say it.
Go ahead.
Tell us what you want.
What I want.
I want.
I want to stay with you forever.
Daddy! Mommy!
You will.
We'll be together forever, Yui.
Yeah.
Remember, you're our child.
It's too late.
For what?
Look,
this is actually a console the GM can use
to gain emergency access to the system.
I used it to delete the
monster in the corridor.
And now, because I disobeyed
the Cardinal's directive,
the system is running
a check on my program.
It thinks I'm a foreign object now.
I'll probably be deleted at once.
Oh, no.
There's got to be a way around it.
Daddy, Mommy, thank you.
This is goodbye.
No!
I don't want that!
Stay with us!
Please stay!
We just started living like a real family!
Yui, don't go!
Whenever the two of you are around,
you have a way of making people smile.
From now on, and for me,
please continue my work.
Keep helping people.
Share your happiness with all
of them. I can't! I won't!
You have to stay with us!
I can't be happy without you!
Smile, Mommy.
Cardinal? No!
Kayaba!
You're going to find out things don't
always go the way you want them to!
Kirito, where are you?
If I'm fast enough, I might be able to
use the GM's account to access the system.
Kirito!
Are you okay?
What's this?
The system was about to reject
Yui's admin credentials.
The only thing I could do was take her
program and turn it into a game object.
So this is...
You're holding Yui's heart.
Hey, Kirito, if the game does
get cleared, and this world ends,
what's going to happen to Yui?
Don't worry,
I fixed it so her data will be saved
to the local memory on my nerve gear.
When we get back, recreating her the
way she was isn't going to be easy,
but if there's away, we'll find it.
Okay.
As long as we can be a family again.
We'll see her when we get back.
Our first child.
Yeah.
We'll see her again.
Hey, Asuna?
You okay?
Good luck, mommy.
I can't believe this dream.
I'm in the front
of the world.
Even if I'm dreaming.
I'm still in the middle of the heart.
It's always, always, always,?
Next time, Edge of Hell's Abyss.